Guide to the Robert Maynard Hutchins Papers 1884-2000
University of Chicago Library
- Series X: Writings
  - Subseries 3: Articles
    - Sub-subseries 1: Articles
      - "Religion and Higher Education," adapted from Hutchins, Freedom, Education, and the Fund, The Commonweal, 29 June 1956 (Box 340, Folder 3)
      - "Ideas, Institutions, and American Liberty," 1957 (Box 340, Folder 4)
      - "Foreword" to Adler, What We Want of Our Schools (1957) (Box 340, Folder 5)
      - "Preface" to Gillowin, Man's Hangman is Man (1957) (Box 340, Folder 6)
      - "The Lesson of Khrushchev's Little Red School House," Esquire, June 1958 (Box 340, Folder 7)
      - "The Age of the Interchangeable Man" ("The New Society"), Esquire, October 1958 (Box 340, Folder 8)
      - "That Candles May be Bought," Recall, 1959, 1959-1964 (Box 340, Folder 9)
      - "The Britannica," Columbia University Forum, Spring 1960 (Box 340, Folder 10)
      - "The Aims of Education," Newsday, 5 March 1960 (Box 340, Folder 11)
      - "Our Educational Program" ("What are Colleges and Universities for?"), McCall's, May 1960 (Box 340, Folder 12)
      - "The Gigantic Task Ahead," TV Guide, 14 May 1960 (Box 340, Folder 13)
      - "Introduction" to Vigdorova, Diary of a Russian Schoolteacher (1960) (Box 340, Folder 14)
      - "Dissenting Opinion as a Creative Act," Saturday Review, 12 August 1961 (Box 340, Folder 15)
      - "Szilard and the Dolphins," review of Szilard, The Voice of the Dolphin (1961), Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, September 1961 (Box 340, Folder 16)
      - "An Approval of American Higher Education," School and Society, 5 May 1962 (Box 340, Folder 17)
      - "Achieving a Perspective on the Tech Order," Tech & Culture, Fall 1962 (Box 340, Folder 18)
      - "The Wall of Separation," including correspondences from readers, Saturday Evening Post, 8 June 1963 (Box 341, Folder 1)
      - "Our Educational Heritage," The Colorado Quarterly, Winter 1963 (Box 341, Folder 2)
      - "A Letter to Reading," Foreword to Gateway to the Great Books (1963) (Box 341, Folder 3)
      - "Introduction" to Hebberd, Artemus Ward, 1963-1964 (Box 341, Folder 4)
      - "Change the Property Tax," California Homeworker, February 1964 (Box 341, Folder 5)
      - "The Time is Now," Reflections on the Role of Liberal Education, Association of American Colleges Bulletin, May 1964 (Box 341, Folder 6)
      - "Science, Scientists, and Politics," The Journal of General Education, October 1964 (Box 341, Folder 7)
      - "Goethe and the Unity of Mankind," 1964 (Box 341, Folder 8)
      - "Are We Educating Our Children for the Wrong Future?" Saturday review, 11 September 1965 (Box 341, Folder 9)
      - "Colleges are Obsolete," The Saturday Evening Post, 25 September 1965 (Box 341, Folder 10)
      - "First Glimpses of a New World," Saturday Review, 4 December 1965 (Box 341, Folder 11)
      - "Foreword," to Wilson-Tauber, Librarian and Administrator (1966) (Box 342, Folder 1)
      - "Natural Law and Jurisprudence," in Natural Law and Modern Society (1966) (Box 342, Folder 2)
      - "Why They Don't Want Business Careers," Think, September – October 1966 (Box 342, Folder 3)
      - "Introduction," to Fleming, Stages in the Cold War Essays 1945-1965, 1967 (Box 342, Folder 4)
      - "The Issues," The University of America, January 1967 (Box 342, Folder 5)
      - "How to Run a University," interview with Independent Star-News, 2 April 1967 (Box 342, Folder 6)
      - "A Chronicle of Issues Affecting Democratic Institute," The Center Magazine, October – November 1967 (Box 342, Folder 7)
      - "The Coming Revolution in the Schools," Los Angeles Times, with correspondence, 18 December 1967 (Box 342, Folder 8)
      - "The Two Faces of Federalism," The Center Magazine, January 1968, 1961, 1968 (Box 342, Folder 9)
      - "The Mind is its Own Place," The Center Magazine, March 1968 (Box 342, Folder 10)
      - "How We Made Lemonade Out of a Lemon," Think, April 1968 (Box 342, Folder 11)
      - "The Report of the President's Commission on Higher Education," The Educational Record, April 1968 (Box 342, Folder 12)
      - "Reforming College Education," a chapter from Hutchins, The Learning Society (1968), Current, June 1968 (Box 343, Folder 1)
      - "Education for a Full Life," Environment and Policy, August 1968 (Box 343, Folder 2)
      - "Permanence and Change," The Center Magazine, September 1968 (Box 343, Folder 3)
      - "In the Thirties," The New York Time Magazine, 8 September 1968 (Box 343, Folder 4)
      - "The Valuator Interviews, Robert M. Hutchins," The Valuator, Fall 1968 (Box 343, Folder 5)
      - "The Limits of Dissent," The Center Magazine, November 1968 (Box 343, Folder 6)
      - "Doing What Comes Scientifically," The Center Magazine, Jan 1969 (Box 343, Folder 7)
      - "The Future of American Education," Manas, 16 April 1969 (Box 343, Folder 8)
      - "A Center Symposium – How should a university administrator respond to radical activism among students?" The Center Magazine, May 1969 (Box 343, Folder 9)
      - "Reclothe Us in Our Rightful Mind," Education Record, Spring 1969 (Box 343, Folder 10)
      - "The Constitution of Public Education," The Center Magazine, July 1969 (Box 343, Folder 11)
      - "The Center in the Sixties and Seventies," The Center Magazine, September 1969 (Box 344, Folder 1)
      - "Public Education Who's Responsible?" The Center Magazine, November 1969 (Box 344, Folder 2)
      - "Living Without Guilt," The Center's Magazine, January 1970 (Box 344, Folder 3)
      - "A Constitutional Forum for Education," The Center Magazine, March 1970 (Box 344, Folder 4)
      - "Manhood and the Liberal Arts," The Urban Review, May 1970 (Box 344, Folder 5)
      - "The Constitution and the Political Community," Education Freedom, Spring-Summer 1970 (Box 344, Folder 6)
      - "They've Gone a Long Way," The Center Magazine, July 1970 (Box 344, Folder 7)
      - "Memorandum from Robert M. Hutchins," The Center Magazine, September 1970 (Box 344, Folder 8)
      - "The Case Constitutional Change," A Center Occasional Paper, December 1970 (Box 344, Folder 9)
      - "What the World Needs Now is Citizens," The Center Magazine, Jan-Feb 1971 (Box 344, Folder 10)
      - "The Limits of Law and Order," The Center Magazine, May-June 1971 (Box 344, Folder 11)
      - "Toward A Learning Society" ("The University in the Learning Society," "The Institutional Illusion"), The Center Magazine, July-August 1971 (Box 344, Folder 12)
      - "Second Education/The Natural Law," The Center Magazine, November 1971 (Box 344, Folder 13)
      - "Implications for Education," Technology, Human Values, and Leisure (1971) (Box 344, Folder 14)
      - "Table Talk – Administering Higher Education," The Center Magazine, May 1972 (Box 344, Folder 15)
      - "Liberal Education for World Citizenship," International Education, Spring 1972 (Box 344, Folder 16)
      - "What I believe," Britannica Roundtable, July 1972 (Box 344, Folder 17)
      - "The Nixon Court and the Bill of Rights," Los Angeles Times, 18 September 1972 (Box 345, Folder 1)
      - "The New Supreme Court," The Center Magazine, September-October 1972 (Box 345, Folder 2)
      - "The Great Anti-School Campaign" ("The School Must Stay," "The Role of Public Education") [1/2], The Great Ideas Today, Fall 1972 (Box 345, Folder 3)
      - "The Great Anti-School Campaign" ("The School Must Stay," "The Role of Public Education"), [2/2], The Great Ideas Today, Fall 1972, 1973 (Box 345, Folder 4)
      - "The Constitution Under Stain," The Center Magazine, March-April 1973 (Box 345, Folder 5)
      - "Nation-State and World Community," a chapter from Hutchins, The Learning Society (1968), International Education, Spring 1973 (Box 345, Folder 6)
      - "地上に平和を (Pacem in Terris)" (Article in Japanese), World: TBSブリタニカ·ジャーナル (Britannica Journal), 1 November 1973 (Box 345, Folder 7)
      - "Desperation in Education," Center Report, December 1973 (Box 345, Folder 8)
      - "St. John's" (Letters), Change, September 1974 (Box 346, Folder 1)
      - "Two Fateful Decisions," The Center Magazine, January-February 1975 (Box 346, Folder 2)
      - "Get Ready for Anything" (Interview), Center Report, June 1975 (Box 346, Folder 3)
      - "Zuckerkandl!" The Center Magazine, see also Zuckerkandl (1968), September-October 1975 (Box 346, Folder 4)
      - "Environment and Civil Rights," The Center Magazine, November-December 1975 (Box 346, Folder 5)
      - "Foreword" to Rosenheim, Pursuing Justice for the Child (1976), 1974-1976 (Box 346, Folder 6)
      - "Is Democracy Possible?" The Center Magazine, January-February 1976 (Box 346, Folder 7)
      - "Who Will Decide Where We Shall Live?" Center Report, April 1976 (Box 346, Folder 8)
      - "An Announcement," Center Report, June 1976 (Box 346, Folder 9)
      - "Front Cover," World Issues, October-November 1976 (Box 346, Folder 10)
      - "Why We Need World Law," World Issues, December 1976 – January 1977 (Box 346, Folder 11)
      - "The Intellectual Community," The Center Magazine, January-February 1977 (Box 346, Folder 12)
      - "A New Foreign Policy Might Be Less Dangerous Than the Old," World Issues, February-March 1977 (Box 346, Folder 13)
      - Miscellaneous Drafts of Articles, ND (Box 346, Folder 14)
      - Unidentified Draft, ND (Box 346, Folder 15)
      - Five Unidentified Manuscripts and Typescripts, 1968, ND (Box 346, Folder 16)
    - Sub-subseries 2: Correspondence
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – A-Ben., December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 346, Folder 17)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – Ber.-Ch., December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 347, Folder 1)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series- Cl.-Di., December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 347, Folder 2)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – Do.-E, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 347, Folder 3)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – F-G, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 347, Folder 4)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – H, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 347, Folder 5)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – I-K, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 347, Folder 6)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – L, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 347, Folder 7)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – M, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 348, Folder 1)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – N-P, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 348, Folder 2)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – Q-R, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 348, Folder 3)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – S-Sp., December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 348, Folder 4)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – St.-V, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 348, Folder 5)
      - Saturday Evening Post – Series – W-Z, December 1937 – December 1941 (Box 348, Folder 6)
      - Saturday Evening Post – General Article Correspondence, December 1936 – September 1941 (Box 348, Folder 7)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "Uncle Sam's Children," A-H, January 1939 – March 1945 (Box 349, Folder 1)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "Uncle Sam's Children," I-Z, January 1939 – March 1945 (Box 349, Folder 2)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "Hutchins on Hutchins," September – November 1938 (Box 349, Folder 3)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "Gate Receipts and Glory," A-F, December 1938 – May 1939 (Box 349, Folder 4)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "Gate Receipts and Glory," G-N, December 1938 – May 1939 (Box 349, Folder 5)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "Gate Receipts and Glory," O-Z, December 1938 – May 1939 (Box 349, Folder 6)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "What Good are Endowments," A-H, November 1939 – August 1940 (Box 349, Folder 7)
      - Saturday Evening Post – "What Good are Endowments," I-Z, November 1939 – August 1940 (Box 349, Folder 8)
      - Correspondence concerning John D. Blaine's Article about Hutchins, June – September 1939 (Box 350, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 1/2, 1962 – 1967 (Box 350, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 2/2, 1967 – 1976 (Box 350, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 1969 – 1970 (Box 350, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 1969 (Box 350, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 1968 – 1969 (Box 350, Folder 6)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 1967 – 1968 (Box 351, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 1967 (Box 351, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, 1966 – 1967 (Box 351, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, Columns No. 151-180, 1966 (Box 351, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, Columns No. 121-150, 1965 (Box 352, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, Columns No. 91-120, 1964-1965 (Box 352, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, Columns No. 61-90, 1964 (Box 352, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, Columns No. 31-60, 1963-1964 (Box 352, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times Syndicate regarding Newspaper Column, Columns No. 1-30, 1963 (Box 352, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times readers regarding Newspaper Column, 1967 (Box 353, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times readers regarding Newspaper Column, 1/2, 1966 (Box 353, Folder 2)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times readers regarding Newspaper Column, 2/2, 1966 (Box 353, Folder 3)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times readers regarding Newspaper Column, 1965 (Box 353, Folder 4)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times readers regarding Newspaper Column [1 of 2], 1964 (Box 353, Folder 5)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times readers regarding Newspaper Column [2 of 2], 1964 (Box 354, Folder 1)
      - Correspondence with Los Angeles Times readers regarding Newspaper Column, 1963 (Box 354, Folder 2)
  - Subseries 4: Speeches
    - Speech at the Yale Class of 1896 Dinner, 27 January 1923 (Box 354, Folder 3)
    - "Experiments in Legal Education at Yale," April 1928 (Box 354, Folder 4)
    - Address at the Sixth Annual Dinner of the American Law Institute, 28 April 1928 (Box 354, Folder 5)
    - "Legal Research in West Virginia," Address at the College of Law at Inauguration of John Roscoe Turner as President of West Virginia University, 28 November 1928 (Box 354, Folder 6)
    - Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 11 June 1929 (Box 354, Folder 7)
    - Inaugural Address as President of the University of Chicago, 19 November 1929 (Box 354, Folder 8)
    - Speech at the Inauguration Dinner of Hutchins as President of the University of Chicago, 19 November 1929 (Box 354, Folder 9)
    - Address to the University of Chicago Student Assembly, 20 November 1929 (Box 354, Folder 10)
    - "The Current of Legal Education," Address before the Kentucky State Bar Association, 4 April 1929 (Box 354, Folder 11)
    - Address before the Teachers Union of Chicago, 2 December 1929 (Box 354, Folder 12)
    - Speech at Trustees' Dinner of the University of Chicago, 8 January 1930 (Box 354, Folder 13)
    - Speech at Alumni's Dinner of the University of Chicago, 22 January 1930 (Box 354, Folder 14)
    - "Chairman's Address," Mid-West Conference on Character Development, February 1930 (Box 355, Folder 1)
    - Address at the First Annual Alumni Assembly of the University of Chicago, 26 February 1930 (Box 355, Folder 2)
    - "The University and the Individual," Address at the Ohio Teachers' Conference, 3 April 1930 (Box 355, Folder 3)
    - "The Trend of Education," address at the inauguration of the State Teachers' Colloquium, Morehead KY, 2 May 1930 (Box 355, Folder 4)
    - "Teaching Today," Commencement Addresses at Richmond and Bowling Green KY, 28-29 May 1930 (Box 355, Folder 5)
    - "Some Educational Questions," Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 10 June 1930 (Box 355, Folder 6)
    - "Education in the Arts,' Commencement Address at the Chicago Art Institute, 20 June 1930 (Box 355, Folder 7)
    - "The University and the Individual," Ohio State Educational Conference, 15 September 1930 (Box 355, Folder 8)
    - An Introduction of James R. Angell, 17 October 1930 (Box 355, Folder 9)
    - "A University of Utopia," ("The Situation in Education"), address at the Southern Conference on Education, Chapel Hill NC, 30 October 1930 (Box 355, Folder 10)
    - "On the Reorganization of the University," 11 November 1930 (Box 355, Folder 11)
    - Address to the Cleveland Phi Beta Kappa Society, Alumni of Western Reserve University, and Alumni of the University of Chicago, 5 December 1930 (Box 355, Folder 12)
    - "The Reorganization of the University of Chicago," Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 23 December 1930 (Box 355, Folder 13)
    - "Education and the University of Chicago," a radio address, 2 January 1931 (Box 355, Folder 14)
    - Speech at Trustees' Dinner of the University of Chicago, 8 January 1931 (Box 355, Folder 15)
    - "The University in 1931," address at the Second Annual Alumni Assembly, 6 March 1931 (Box 355, Folder 16)
    - "The Vast Importance of Ireland," Address at the Annual Banquet of the Irish Fellowship Club of Chicago, 17 March 1931 (Box 355, Folder 17)
    - Address before North Central Association, 19 March 1931 (Box 355, Folder 18)
    - "Education for Research and Teaching," Address before the Association of the Doctors of Philosophy, 4 April 1931 (Box 355, Folder 19)
    - "Commencement Address," Berea College, 1 June 1931 (Box 355, Folder 20)
    - "The Upper Divisions of the University of Chicago," Address to the Institute for Administrative Officers of Higher Institutions for 1931 at the University of Chicago, 9 July 1931 (Box 355, Folder 21)
    - "The New Atlantis," Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 16 June 1931 (Box 355, Folder 22)
    - "The Chicago Plan and Graduate Study," address at the Association of American Universities' Annual Conference, 13 November 1931 (Box 355, Folder 23)
    - "The Professor Says" ("The Tenure of Professors"), Speech at the Annual Dinner of the American Association of University Professors, 27-28 November 1931 (Box 355, Folder 24)
    - Dedication of the Oriental Institute, 5 December 1931 (Box 355, Folder 25)
    - Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 20 December 1931 (Box 355, Folder 26)
    - "Economics and Psychology by Radio," Radio Address broadcast by the NBC, 2 January 1932 (Box 355, Folder 27)
    - Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 20 December 1931, also Address at the Trustees' Dinner to the Faculties, 14 January 1932 (Box 356, Folder 1)
    - "Education as a National Enterprise," Address before the Department of Superintendent of the National Educational Association," 25 February 1932 (Box 356, Folder 2)
    - Welcoming Address at the Goethe Centennial, 8 March 1932 (Box 356, Folder 3)
    - Goethe Centennial Welcome Address, June 1932 (Box 356, Folder 4)
    - "A Democratic Platform," Speech to the Young Democratic Clubs, 27 June 1932 (Box 356, Folder 5)
    - "To Students Entering the College," speech at the University of Chicago, 1 September 1932 (Box 356, Folder 6)
    - "The Higher Learning in America," speech at Cleveland OH, 28 October 1932 (Box 356, Folder 7)
    - Remarks at the memorial Service for Martin A. Ryerson at the Chicago Art Institute, 11 November 1932 (Box 356, Folder 8)
    - "The New Tool," introductory remarks at the exhibition "Taking Motion Pictures," 14 November 1932 (Box 356, Folder 9)
    - Speech at the Union League Club, 16 December 1932 (Box 356, Folder 10)
    - "Prospects of Higher Education," Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 20 December 1932 (Box 356, Folder 11)
    - Speech at the Trustees' Dinner to the Faculties, 12 January 1933 (Box 356, Folder 12)
    - "Education as a National Asset and Responsibility" ("Our American Schools"), Radio Speech broadcast by the NBC, 12 February 1933 (Box 356, Folder 13)
    - "New Frontiers in the University Area," Address before the Department of Superintendence, 2 March 1933 (Box 356, Folder 14)
    - "The Professor is Sometimes Rights," speech to the Bond Club of New York, 17 May 1933 (Box 356, Folder 15)
    - "Adult Education and the YMCA," Address at the 45th Conference of the Association of Employed Officers, YMCA of North America, 9 June 1933 (Box 356, Folder 16)
    - Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 13 June 1933 (Box 356, Folder 17)
    - Commencement Address at the Lewis Institute, 22 June 1933 (Box 356, Folder 18)
    - "Education and the Public Mind," Address before the National Education Association, 6 July 1933 (Box 356, Folder 19)
    - "Back to Galen," Convocation Address at the American College of Surgeons, 13 October 1933 (Box 356, Folder 20)
    - "The Proposed Merger," Address to the Undergraduates at the University of Chicago, 12 December 1933 (Box 357, Folder 1)
    - "The Autobiography of an Ex-Law Student," Address at Annual Banquet of the Association of American Law Students, 29 December 1933 (Box 357, Folder 2)
    - "The Higher Learning II," speech at the Trustees' Dinner to Faculty, 11 January 1934 (Box 357, Folder 3)
    - Address at the Mid-Winter Dinner of the University of Chicago, April 1934 (Box 357, Folder 4)
    - "The Educational Function of New England," Stearns Lecture before Philips Academy, 17 April 1934 (Box 357, Folder 5)
    - "Democracy and the Higher Learning," Address at the Honors Convocation of the University of Michigan, 27 April 1934 (Box 357, Folder 6)
    - Speech at the Daily Maroon Annual Dinner, 23 May 1934 (Box 357, Folder 7)
    - "The Sentimental Alumnus," Speech at Oberlin College Commencement, June 1934 (Box 357, Folder 8)
    - "The Organization of A University," Convocation Address at the University of Chicago, 12 June 1934 (Box 357, Folder 9)
    - Speech at Oberlin College, 19 June 1934 (Box 357, Folder 10)
    - "The Teacher, the School, and the National Life," Address to National Education Association, September 1934 (Box 357, Folder 11)
    - "Radio and Public Policy," Address before the National Advisory Council on Radio in Education, 8 October 1934 (Box 357, Folder 12)
    - "The Future of the University," 10 January 1935 (Box 357, Folder 13)
    - "The Outlook for Education," Address before the Council of Administration of the Kansas State Teachers Association, 8 February 1935 (Box 357, Folder 14)
    - Annual report to Alumni at the Winter Assembly of the University of Chicago Alumni, 21 February 1935 (Box 357, Folder 15)
    - Report to Alumni at Mid-Winter Dinner, March 1935 (Box 357, Folder 16)
    - "International Economics Relations," address at the Houston Open Forum, 19 March 1935 (Box 357, Folder 17)
    - "What is a University?" speech at the University of Chicago, broadcast by the NBC, 18 April 1935 (Box 357, Folder 18)
    - "Function of a University," Radio Address, 25 April 1935 (Box 357, Folder 19)
    - "Teaching at the University," Statement to the Illinois State Legislature, 13 May 1935 (Box 357, Folder 20)
    - "The Future of World Trade," radio address broadcast by the NBC, 22 May 1935 (Box 357, Folder 21)
    - Commencement Address at the University of Chicago, 11 June 1935 (Box 358, Folder 1)